taylormadegolf.com 2018-04-14

# Legal/Privacy - TaylorMade Golf

  * Legal
  * Your Privacy Rights

**Legal**

**Terms and Conditions of Website Usage Agreement**

**Last Revised: October 2, 2017**

Thank you for visiting the Terms and Conditions (the "Terms") page of Taylor Made Golf Company, Inc. ("TaylorMade"). Your access and use of any of our websites at [taylormadegolf.com](http://www.taylormadegolf.com/), [adamsgolf.com](http://www.adamsgolf.com/),  [ashworthgolf.com](http://www.ashworthgolf.com/), [tmagdirect.com](http://www.tmagdirect.com/), [tmag.biz](http://www.tmag.biz/), and all other TaylorMade websites (the "TaylorMade Websites") is subject to the following terms and applicable laws.

Certain services or other offerings made available on the TaylorMade Websites may have additional terms and conditions that apply, and which can be viewed either on the pages containing such services or offerings, or via a link on those pages or other directions to the additional terms and conditions.

BY USING THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES, YOU ARE AGREEING TO THESE TERMS WITHOUT LIMITATION OR QUALIFICATION, AS WELL AS SUCH ADDITIONAL OR AMENDED TERMS AND CONDITIONS AS TMAG MAY FROM TIME TO TIME PUBLISH.

**Eligibility**

You must be at least 13 years old to use the TaylorMade Websites.  If you are under the age of majority in your state of residence, a minor, your parent or legal guardian must agree to these Terms on your behalf and you may only access and use the TaylorMade Websites with permission from your parent or legal guardian.

**Intellectual Property**

The TaylorMade Websites are owned and operated by TaylorMade and/or its affiliates, and are protected by copyright law and other United States and international laws and treaties. All rights reserved. Copyright in the content and the software provided are owned by or licensed to TaylorMade.

Materials from the TaylorMade Websites may not be copied, distributed or transmitted in any way without the prior written consent of TaylorMade. No links to the TaylorMade Websites may be created without the express written consent of TaylorMade. Subject to the limitations and restrictions stated herein, users of the TaylorMade Websites MAY download one copy of any and all materials on the site for personal, non-commercial use, provided they do not modify or alter the materials in any way, or delete or change any copyright or trademark notice.

Unless otherwise noted, products, product names, designs, logos, text, images, graphics, audio, video, code, domain names, organization, and user look-and-feel within the TaylorMade Websites are the trademarks, service marks, trade names, copyrights, patents, or other property of TaylorMade (“TaylorMade Intellectual Property”).  Unauthorized use of the materials from the TaylorMade Websites may violate copyright, trademark, and other laws.  Nothing on the TaylorMade Websites should be construed as granting, by implication, estoppel, or otherwise, any license or right to use any TaylorMade Intellectual Property displayed on the TaylorMade Websites without the express, written permission of TaylorMade.  All rights not expressly granted herein are reserved.

All material on the TaylorMade Websites is provided for lawful purposes only. Images of people or places in the TaylorMade Websites are either the property of or used with permission by TaylorMade. The use or misuse of those images except as expressly authorized is prohibited. TaylorMade reserves complete title and full intellectual property rights in materials downloaded from the site.

We pride ourselves on innovation and quality in the design and manufacturing of TaylorMade products. Consequently, TaylorMade golf products are protected by a variety of patents, trademarks, and other rights granted to TaylorMade under international, federal, state, statutory, and common law. These rights not only recognize the innovation and distinctiveness of TaylorMade's intellectual property rights in its products and brands, but also afford legal protection to TaylorMade from infringements of these property rights. Our policy is to diligently enforce all intellectual property rights. We will work to locate and prosecute those who infringe on these rights.

The following is a non-exhaustive list of the trademarks owned or licensed by TaylorMade that are used on or in connection with TaylorMade products:

In accordance with Section 287(a) of Title 35 of the United States Code, the reader is hereby placed on notice of Taylor Made Golf Company's rights in the United States Patents listed on this site and associated with the following products.

Other U.S. and Foreign patents pending.

Taylor Made Golf Company, Inc. comprises three premium brands, TaylorMade, Adams, and Ashworth. TAYLORMADE, the TaylorMade Logo, the Stylized T Design, Ashworth, the Golfman Logo, and Adams are registered trademarks of TaylorMade Golf Company, Inc. All other trademarks and service marks used herein are property of their respective owners.

Any information, including but not limited to remarks, suggestions, ideas, graphics or other submissions, communicated to TaylorMade through this site is not confidential. TaylorMade shall be entitled to reproduce, distribute or use any such information submitted for any purpose without compensation to the person sending the submission.

The user acknowledges the originality of any submission communicated to TaylorMade and accepts responsibility for its accuracy, appropriateness and legality.

**Prohibited Activities**

You agree not to: (i) share usernames, passwords or other access credentials that allow access to protected portions of any TaylorMade Website by any unauthorized third party; (ii) engage in or facilitate spamming; (iii) post, disseminate or transmit unauthorized advertising, promotional materials, chain letters, junk mail or any other type of unsolicited mass e-mail to people or entities that have not agreed to be part of such mailings; (iv) omit, delete, forge or misrepresent transmission information, including headers, return mailing and Internet protocol addresses, or otherwise manipulate identifiers to disguise the origin of any content; (v) impersonate any person or entity, or falsely state or otherwise misrepresent an affiliation with any person or entity; (vi) disseminate or transmit any content without the right to do so; (vii) send harassing and/or threatening messages to others; (viii) post excessive (20 or more copies of the same article in a 45-day period) or repeated off-topic articles to newsgroups; (ix) engage in 'flooding', i.e., ICMP flooding and mail bombing (flooding as used herein is defined as sending large amounts of email repeatedly to the same email address).

**Content Restrictions**

You agree not to post, disseminate or transmit any content that: (i) is unlawful, harassing, defamatory, abusive, threatening, obscene, harmful, tortious, libelous, or invasive of another's privacy; (ii) infringes or violates any party's author's right, trademark, trade secret, patent or other proprietary right, including but not limited to using third party materials protected by author's right law without appropriate permission, using third party trademarks without appropriate permission or attribution, and using or distributing third party information whether or not protected as a trade secret in violation of a duty of confidentiality; (iii) you do not have the right to disseminate or transmit under law, or contractual or fiduciary relationships; or (iv) contains personally identifiable information belonging to minors.

**Unlawful Behavior**

You agree not to: (i) use the TaylorMade Websites for any illegal purpose, in violation of any applicable laws or regulations including but not limited to, regulations promulgated by the Securities Exchange Commission, any rules of any national or other securities exchange, including without limitation, the New York Stock Exchange, the American Stock Exchange or the NASDAQ, and any regulations having the force of law; (ii) publish web pages that contain links that initiate downloads of infringing or other illegal material; (iii) electronically stalk or otherwise electronically harass another; (iv) engage in any Internet activities that would violate the personal privacy rights of others, including but not limited to, collecting and distributing information about Internet users without their permission, except as permitted by applicable law; or (v) conduct Internet raffles or contests that violate applicable laws.

**Disruptive Behavior**

As a further condition of your use of and access to the TaylorMade Websites, you agree not to: (i) post, disseminate or transmit any worm, viruses or other harmful, disruptive or destructive files, code or programs via or through the TaylorMade Websites; (ii) use Internet Relay Chat (IRC) bots, i.e., programs that utilize excessive resources by connecting to an IRC network and running 24 hours per day; (iii) hinder the ability of others to use IRC; (iv) disrupt the normal flow on the TaylorMade Websites of dialogue or otherwise act in a manner that negatively affects other users' ability to engage in real time exchanges; (v) run any program that makes a service or resource available to others, including but not limited to port redirectors, proxy servers, chat servers or Multi-User Dungeons; (vi) interfere with, disrupt, or harm in any way the TaylorMade Websites or servers or networks connected to them; (vii) run programs or specifically configure machines in such a way as to keep a dialup connection active when not in use or otherwise bypass automatic disconnection for inactivity, unless a dedicated access account is provided; (viii) use the TaylorMade Websites in violation of the rules of any other website providers, websites, chat rooms or the like; (ix) use the TaylorMade Websites to access the accounts of others without permission; (x) attempt to penetrate security measures of TaylorMade or another entity, or obtain or bypass others' passwords; or (xi) engage in denial of service attacks, i.e., actions designed to impair network access by flooding a site or the Internet with useless traffic. 

**Opinions, Views and Recommendations of Third Party Contractors**

TaylorMade, in its sole discretion, may utilize third party contractors for various customer service functions, including without limitation interactive chats with product specialists relating to product recommendations.  Opinions, views and recommendations expressed by such third parties are not necessarily the opinions, views and recommendations of TaylorMade, and TaylorMade is not responsible for any such opinions, views or recommendations made by such third parties.

**Disclaimer and Limitation of Liability**

BY USING THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES, YOU EXPRESSLY AGREE THAT USE OF THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK. THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES ARE PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" AND "AS AVAILABLE" BASIS. TAYLORMADE DOES NOT WARRANT THAT USE OF THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES WILL BE UNINTERRUPTED OR ERROR-FREE. TAYLORMADE RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CANCEL ANY ORDER FOR TAYLORMADE PRODUCTS PLACED ON THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITE AS A RESULT OF A MISTAKE OR ERROR, AS DETERMINED BY TAYLORMADE IN ITS SOLE DISCRETION.  TAYLORMADE DOES NOT WARRANT THE ACCURACY, INTEGRITY OR COMPLETENESS OF THE CONTENT PROVIDED ON THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES OR THE PRODUCTS OR SERVICES OFFERED FOR SALE ON THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES. TAYLORMADE SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES, WHETHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO WARRANTIES OF TITLE, MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TO THE FULLEST EXTENT POSSIBLE UNDER LAW. NO VERBAL INFORMATION PROVIDED BY TAYLORMADE SHALL CREATE A WARRANTY. UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES SHALL TAYLORMADE BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES THAT RESULT FROM YOUR USE OF OR INABILITY TO USE THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO RELIANCE BY YOU ON ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED FROM THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES THAT RESULTS IN MISTAKES, OMISSIONS, INTERRUPTIONS, DELETION OR CORRUPTION OF FILES, VIRUSES, DELAYS IN OPERATION OR TRANSMISSION, OR ANY FAILURE OF PERFORMANCE. THE FOREGOING LIMITATION OF LIABILITY SHALL APPLY WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION, EVEN IF AN AUTHORIZED REPRESENTATIVE OF TAYLORMADE HAS BEEN ADVISED OF OR SHOULD HAVE KNOWLEDGE OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES, HOWEVER, THE FOREGOING SHALL NOT APPLY TO THE EXTENT THAT ANY LIABILITY IS THE RESULT OF OUR OWN NEGLIGENCE. THIS PARAGRAPH SHALL APPLY TO ALL CONTENT, MERCHANDISE AND SERVICES AVAILABLE THROUGH THE WEBSITE.

TO THE FULLEST EXTENT POSSIBLE UNDER LAW, TAYLORMADE’S TOTAL CUMULATIVE LIABILITY TO YOU OR ANY THIRD PARTY UNDER THESE TERMS, FROM ALL CAUSES OF ACTION AND ALL THEORIES OF LIABILITY, WILL BE LIMITED TO AND WILL NOT EXCEED THE AMOUNTS YOU HAVE ACTUALLY PAID TAYLORMADE DURING THE TWELVE (12) MONTHS PRECEDING THE CLAIM GIVING RISE TO SUCH LIABILITY. 

**Products, Content and Specifications**

 All features, content, specifications, products and prices of products and services described or depicted on the TaylorMade Websites are subject to change at any time without notice. Certain weights, measures and similar descriptions are approximate and are provided for convenience purposes only. We make all reasonable efforts to accurately display the attributes of our products, including the applicable colors; however, the actual color you see will depend on your computer system, and we cannot guarantee that your computer will accurately display such colors. The inclusion of any products or services on the TaylorMade Websites at a particular time does not imply or warrant that these products or services will be available at any time.  From time to time, certain product listings on the TaylorMade Websites may show a product’s original price stricken through, alongside a reduced price.  These products may be non-current models and may be on permanent markdown. 

**Applicability of Content**

Information on this site includes description of products and services that may be available in the United States of America only. This site is operated in the State of California, United States of America, and TaylorMade makes no representation that the content provided is applicable or appropriate for use in other locations.

**Arbitration Agreement & Waiver of Certain Rights**

You and TaylorMade agree that we will resolve any disputes between us through binding and final arbitration instead of through court proceedings. You and TaylorMade hereby waive any right to a jury trial of any Claim. All controversies, claims, counterclaims, or other disputes arising between you and TaylorMade relating to these Terms or the TaylorMade Websites (each a “Claim”) shall be submitted for binding arbitration in accordance with the Rules of the American Arbitration Association (“AAA Rules”) in San Diego, California. The arbitration will be heard and determined by a single arbitrator. The arbitrator's decision in any such arbitration will be final and binding upon the parties and may be enforced in any court of competent jurisdiction. The parties agree that the arbitration will be kept confidential and that the existence of the proceeding and any element of it (including, without limitation, any pleadings, briefs or other documents submitted or exchanged and any testimony or other oral submissions and awards) will not be disclosed beyond the arbitration proceedings, except as may lawfully be required in judicial proceedings relating to the arbitration or by applicable disclosure rules and regulations of securities regulatory authorities or other governmental agencies.

If you demonstrate that the costs of arbitration will be prohibitive as compared to the costs of litigation, TaylorMade will pay as much of the administrative costs and arbitrator's fees required for the arbitration as the arbitrator deems necessary to prevent the cost of the arbitration from being prohibitive. In the final award, the arbitrator may apportion the costs of arbitration and the compensation of the arbitrator among the parties in such amounts as the arbitrator deems appropriate.

 This arbitration agreement does not preclude you or TaylorMade from seeking action by federal, state, or local government agencies. You and TaylorMade also have the right to bring qualifying claims in small claims court. In addition, you and TaylorMade retain the right to apply to any court of competent jurisdiction for provisional relief, including pre-arbitral attachments or preliminary injunctions, and any such request shall not be deemed incompatible with these Terms, nor a waiver of the right to have disputes submitted to arbitration as provided in these Terms.  

Neither you nor TaylorMade may act as a class representative or private attorney general, nor participate as a member of a class of claimants, with respect to any Claim. Claims may not be arbitrated on a class or representative basis. The arbitrator can decide only your and/or TaylorMade’s individual Claims. The arbitrator may not consolidate or join the claims of other persons or parties who may be similarly situated.  

If any provision of this Section is found to be invalid or unenforceable, then that specific provision shall be of no force and effect and shall be severed, but the remainder of this Section shall continue in full force and effect. No waiver of any provision of this Section of the Terms will be effective or enforceable unless recorded in a writing signed by the party waiving such a right or requirement. Such a waiver shall not waive or affect any other portion of this Terms. This Section of the Terms will survive the termination of your relationship with TaylorMade.  

THIS SECTION LIMITS CERTAIN RIGHTS, INCLUDING THE RIGHT TO MAINTAIN A COURT ACTION, THE RIGHT TO A JURY TRIAL, THE RIGHT TO PARTICIPATE IN ANY FORM OF CLASS OR REPRESENTATIVE CLAIM, THE RIGHT TO ENGAGE IN DISCOVERY EXCEPT AS PROVIDED IN AAA RULES, AND THE RIGHT TO CERTAIN REMEDIES AND FORMS OF RELIEF. OTHER RIGHTS THAT YOU OR TAYLORMADE WOULD HAVE IN COURT ALSO MAY NOT BE AVAILABLE IN ARBITRATION.

**Privacy**

We realize that consumers are concerned about how the information they provide online will be used. Please read our [Privacy Policy](http://taylormadegolf.com/about-us/privacy.html#privacy) for more details. 

**Enforcement of Terms and Conditions**

These Terms are governed and interpreted pursuant to the laws of the State of California, United States of America, without reference to its provisions concerning conflicts of law.

Without limiting the arbitration agreement set forth above, you agree that any action of whatever nature arising from or relating to these Terms or the TaylorMade Websites will be filed only in the state or federal courts located in the County of San Diego, State of California). You consent and submit to the personal jurisdiction of such courts for the purposes of any such action.

If any part of these Terms is unlawful, void, or unenforceable, that part will be deemed severable and will not affect the validity and enforceability of the remaining provisions. TaylorMade may revise these Terms at any time by updating this posting.

Under no circumstances will TaylorMade be held liable for any delay or failure in performance due in whole or in part to any acts of nature or other causes beyond its reasonable control.

The failure by us to enforce any right or provision of these Terms will not prevent TaylorMade from enforcing such right or provision in the future.

TaylorMade may assign our rights and obligations under these Terms, including in connection with a merger, acquisition, sale of assets or equity, or by operation of law.

TaylorMade reserves the right to not provide the TaylorMade websites to any person.  TaylorMade also reserves the right to terminate any user’s right to access the TaylorMade websites at any time, in its discretion.  If you violate any of these Terms, your permission to use the TaylorMade websites automatically terminates.

From time to time, TaylorMade may change these Terms.  If TaylorMade changes these Terms, it will give you notice by posting the revised Terms on the TaylorMade Websites.  Those changes will go into effect on the Revision Date shown in the revised Terms.  BY CONTINUING TO USE THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES, YOU ARE AGREEING TO THE REVISED TERMS. 

PLEASE PRINT A COPY OF THESE TERMS FOR YOU RECORDS AND PLEASE CHECK THE TAYLORMADE WEBSITES FREQUENTLY FOR ANY CHANGES TO THESE TERMS.

**Your Privacy Rights**

Last Revised: October 2, 2017

Thank you for visiting the Privacy Policy of Taylor Made Golf Company, Inc. ("TaylorMade"). TaylorMade values your privacy, and wants you to feel comfortable and secure using any of our websites, including: [taylormadegolf.com](http://taylormadegolf.com/), [adamsgolf.com](http://adamsgolf.com/), [ashworthgolf.com](http://ashworthgolf.com/), [tmagdirect.com](http://www.tmagdirect.com/), [tmag.biz](http://www.tmag.biz/), all other TaylorMade websites, and any TaylorMade mobile or other applications or apps (the "TaylorMade Websites"). This Privacy Policy describes our policy with regard to online privacy and explains how you can opt out of certain uses and disclosures of your personal information.  As a courtesy, this Privacy Policy also provides a number of useful links to third party information regarding privacy protection. However, TaylorMade does not assume any responsibility for the accuracy and/or completeness of such third party information.

Your Acceptance

By visiting, using, and/or registering on any of the TaylorMade Websites, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not so agree, you should not use the TaylorMade Websites. Should we make any substantial changes in the way we collect and/or use any personal information we will amend this Privacy Policy, and we may email you, and your continued use of any TaylorMade Websites constitutes your consent to the amended Privacy Policy.

TaylorMade Websites

This Privacy Policy applies only to the TaylorMade Websites. Links within these sites could direct you to third party websites that are not owned or controlled by TaylorMade. TaylorMade has no control over, and assumes no responsibility for, the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third party websites, which may employ cookies and/or collect personal information. In addition, TaylorMade will not and cannot censor or edit the content of any third party site. We encourage you to be aware when you leave the TaylorMade Websites, and to read the privacy policy of each website that you visit.

TaylorMade affiliates may have their own privacy policy governing websites other than the above TaylorMade Websites.

What Type of Personal Information Do We Collect and Use?

Whenever you register a TaylorMade product, send us an email, purchase products from a TaylorMade Website, register on one of the TaylorMade Websites, enter a contest, sweepstakes, or other promotion, subscribe to one of our newsletters, or otherwise transmit information via any of the TaylorMade Websites, TaylorMade may obtain and collect personally identifiable information (expressed herein generally as "personal information") such as your name, email address, payment information (i.e. credit card number/expiration date), and/or mailing address, subject to your ability to "opt-out" of our future use or disclosure of such information as detailed in this Privacy Policy.

Personal Information Maintenance & Opt-Out

If you wish to opt-out of our use and/or disclosure of your personal information, other than to process any purchase orders and communicate with you about your account, you will generally have the option to do so when you first submit your personal information via the TaylorMade Websites. Simply indicate your desire to opt-out by checking or un-checking the appropriate box. If you wish to amend or delete any personal information you have previously provided without opting out, please send us a message at [privacy@tmag.com](mailto:privacy@tmag.com). We will endeavor to provide a simple way to review, correct, update or remove personal information you have given us. If you wish to stop receiving a TaylorMade newsletter that you have previously subscribed for or any other marketing communications, please follow the "unsubscribe" instructions contained at the bottom of each newsletter or email.

How Do We Use Personal Information?

TaylorMade will only disclose your email address to select third party retailers when the email is collected via a TaylorMade mobile fitting application at participating fitting locations, to TaylorMade subsidiary and affiliated companies, as otherwise disclosed in this Privacy Policy, or with your express permission.

TaylorMade may use personal information in the following ways:

  * to enable us to respond to you generally, or to process, validate and verify requests and/or purchase orders
  * to perform any services requested by you
  * to compile and/or distribute aggregate information about our website users and aggregate usage patterns
  * to provide our own website designers with useful information for developing new features and services that meet your needs
  * to tailor your experience on our websites and our communications with you, showing you content and sending you information we think might interest you or altering the content and our communications according to your personal preferences and interests
  * as part of an online employment application to evaluate your qualifications only
  * to share with government agencies, law enforcement, or with third parties if we think we are legally obligated, or to protect ourselves.  For example, we will disclose information in response to subpoenas, investigative requests, and reasonable discovery requests.

If you have not "opted-out" of our use and disclosure of your personal information, TaylorMade may also use personal information for all marketing and survey purposes on behalf of itself and its affiliates and subsidiaries. TaylorMade may appoint third party agents in connection with such marketing and survey efforts. TaylorMade may disclose personal information to select business partners for use in connection with direct mail marketing efforts, including, without limitation, with select third party retailers when the email is collected via a TaylorMade mobile fitting application at participating fitting locations and with TaylorMade subsidiary companies.

TaylorMade may share your personal information and other data with businesses controlling, controlled by, or under common control with TaylorMade.  If TaylorMade is merged, acquired, or sold, or in the event of a transfer of some or all of its assets, TaylorMade may disclose or transfer your personal information and other data in connection with such transaction.  You will have the opportunity to opt out of any such transfer if, in TaylorMade’s discretion, it will result in the handling of your personal information in a way that differs materially from this Privacy Policy. 

From time to time TaylorMade might establish a business relationship with other persons or entities whom it believes are trustworthy and whom it has asked to confirm that their privacy policies are consistent with TaylorMade’s.  These are known as TaylorMade’s “Select Partners.”  In such cases TaylorMade might rent, exchange, share and/or cross-reference information, including personal information about you, that will enable such persons or entities to contact you regarding products and services that may be of interest to you.  You may opt-out of data sharing with Select Partners as described in the “Personal Information Maintenance & Opt-Out” Section above.

If you have "opted-out", TaylorMade will use or disclose your personal information only as stated above, or: (1) when legally ordered to do so by a lawful subpoena or court order, (2) if you violate or breach an agreement with TaylorMade, (3) if we believe you will harm the property or rights of TaylorMade or those of TaylorMade's other customers, (4) under exigent circumstances to protect the physical safety of TaylorMade, its employees, users or the general public, or (5) to validate credit card numbers for charging for fee services.

Aggregate Information

TaylorMade may share aggregate statistical information with business partners, sponsors or other third parties. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of visitors visited a certain area on a website, or that Y number of men and Z number of women filled out registration forms.

Unsolicited Emails Received by You

TaylorMade does not send unsolicited bulk emails to anyone who has requested that we do not contact them. We send our newsletters only to those who have subscribed to receive them. If you have inadvertently received one of our newsletters or other marketing communication, or if you simply wish to stop receiving them, please follow the "unsubscribe" instructions contained in each newsletter or send a request to be unsubscribed to [privacy@tmag.com](mailto:privacy@tmag.com).

TaylorMade Text Message Programs

TaylorMade offers various text message programs from time to time.  If you have consented to receive text messages from TaylorMade, you can opt-out of receiving future text messages at any time.  Please see the terms and conditions applicable to your specific text message program to learn more, including how to opt-out of receiving future text messages.  Message & Data Rates May Apply.  For customer service, please contact us at 1.866.530.TMAG (8624) between 6 AM and 5 PM, Monday thru Friday.

Chat Rooms and Forums

The TaylorMade Websites may now or in the future include chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. You should exercise caution before disclosing your personal information via these public venues, which you do at your own risk. If you do so, you may receive unsolicited emails or "spam" from others. TaylorMade cannot safeguard the privacy of personal information that is disclosed online in this manner.

Our Cookies

Your browser software includes a feature called "cookies." If enabled, cookies may store small amounts of data on your computer about your visit to any of the TaylorMade Websites. Cookies assist us in tracking which of our features you visit most often and what content you may have viewed during past visits. When you re-visit the TaylorMade Websites, cookies can enable us to customize our content according to your preferences. We may use cookies to:

  * keep count of return visits to the TaylorMade Websites
  * accumulate and report anonymous, aggregate, statistical information on website usage
  * deliver content and advertising specific to your interests or past viewing history

You can also disable cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you can accept or reject all cookies, or request a notification when a cookie is set.

IP Addresses

TaylorMade does not store or record the Internet Protocol ("IP") addresses of visitors to the TaylorMade Websites for marketing purposes, although we may store IP addresses in server logs for features such as to keep your shopping cart active, for system maintenance purposes, or to store the source location whenever someone provides Personal Information. An IP address is a number assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. An Internet Service Providers ("ISP") typically assigns a random IP addresses at the time of your dial-up. For local area network ("LAN"), DSL, or cable modem users, an IP address may be permanently assigned to a particular computer. We cannot determine your identity solely based upon your IP address. Your IP address can, however, reveal what geographic area you are connecting from, or which ISP you are using. Finally, other websites you visit have IP addresses, and we may collect the IP addresses of those websites and their pages, but these IP addresses are never associated with Internet users.

Web Beacons

The TaylorMade Websites and certain emails sent to opt-in consumers contain electronic images (called "pixels", "transparent GIF files", or "web beacons") that allow us and our advertising partners to view and access cookies. In general, any electronic image viewed as part of a web page, including an ad banner, can act as a web beacon. Web beacons are small in order not to use valuable space on the computer screen that is better used to display helpful content. In some cases these files are provided by our online management partner. These files enable our online management partner to recognize a unique cookie on your web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to the TaylorMade Websites. The cookie was placed by us or by another advertiser that works with our online management partner. We may also include web beacons in HTML-formatted newsletters and other emails containing graphics that we send, so we may count the number of newsletters and emails that have been opened and read.

Advertising and Online Tracking

We may also use the web beacon and cookies to monitor your online behavior and interests on the TaylorMade Websites and communications from TaylorMade to tailor advertisements and other communications shown and sent to you for goods and services. With both cookies and web beacons, the information stored by the web beacon or cookie does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address. Our systems do not recognize browser “Do Not Track” signals, but several of our service providers who utilize these cookies and other tracking technologies on the TaylorMade Websites enable you to opt out of this type of advertising. For more information about third party cookies and web beacons, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, [click here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_cookies) or click [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). We also provide you with additional tools to opt out of marketing from us or certain transfers of your information. Please see the “Personal Information Maintenance & Opt-Out” section of this Privacy Policy for more information.

Computer Profiles

TaylorMade may also collect and accumulate other anonymous data that helps us understand and analyze the Internet experience of our visitors. For example, we may accumulate visitor data relating to referring domain names, the type of browsers used, operating system software, screen resolutions, color capabilities, browser plug-ins, language settings, cookie preferences, search engine keywords and JavaScript enablement. If you do not register on one of the TaylorMade Websites, none of this information is personally identifiable.

Security

The TaylorMade Websites use physical, electronic and managerial security measures to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of information under our control.

  * We use Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") connections with 128-bit encryption for certain transactions and confidential data. When you use a secure browser, all information you submit comes to us over the Internet in an encrypted form. Every secure page uses a digital certificate issued by a third-party certification authority. A "site certificate" sits on all secure pages. To view this certificate, click on the image of the closed lock or the solid key on the bottom bar of your browser window.
  * We monitor system and application activity logs to identify any unusual activity from authorized and/or unauthorized individuals accessing our systems and/or making changes to stored information. We regularly perform preventative system maintenance and monitoring to ensure the security of our data systems.
  * We maintain our servers in locked facilities with secure access. Backup tapes are retrieved daily and stored by an independent company in a secure, off-site location.

The TaylorMade Websites do not require you to set up a user ID and password unless you subscribe for some of our special services or create a purchasing account with us. We recommend you do not divulge your password to anyone. TaylorMade will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited telephone call or email.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit, and you do so at your own risk. You can report network abuse and any risk of security violations to us by emailing [privacy@tmag.com](mailto:privacy@tmag.com).

Children's Online Privacy Protection

TaylorMade does not knowingly collect contact or personal information from children under 13.  The TaylorMade Websites are not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13.  If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete such information from our records.  If you want to notify us of our receipt of information by children under 13, please do so by emailing us at [privacy@tmag.com](mailto:privacy@tmag.com).

California users under the age of 18 may request the removal of their content or information publicly posted on the TaylorMade Websites by e-mailing us at [privacy@tmag.com](mailto:privacy@tmag.com).  Please note that most of the user content that appears on the TaylorMade Websites is stored and controlled by third party providers; thus, complete and comprehensive removal of the content may not be possible.

Notice to California Residents/Your California Privacy Rights

California residents are entitled once a year to request and obtain certain information regarding our disclosure, if any, of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes during the immediately prior calendar year.  As set forth in this Privacy Policy, we comply with this law by offering our visitors the ability to tell us not to share their personally identifiable information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes.  To make such a request, consistently exercise your opt-out choice whenever you provide personally identifiable information to us or send us an email at [privacy@tmag.com](mailto:privacy@tmag.com).  You must use the website address for this website as the subject line, and include your full name, e-mail address, and postal address in your message.

European Union and Swiss Residents

If you choose to provide TaylorMade with your information, you consent to the transfer and storage of that information on our servers located in the United States.

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of your information should be directed to TaylorMade by calling us at 760-918-6000 or sending us an email at [privacy@tmag.com](mailto:privacy@tmag.com). We will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Contact Information

If you have any questions concerning this Privacy Policy, you may contact the TaylorMade Legal Department:

TaylorMade Golf Company  
Attn: Legal Department  
5545 Fermi Court  
Carlsbad, CA 92008-7324  
USA  
Phone: +1 760-918-6000  
Fax: +1 760-918-6008

Email: privacy@tmag.com
